（A24影业）
（切宁娱乐）
（21 Laps娱乐公司）
（原子怪兽影业）
出品公司
北路影业
A24影业
制作公司
21 Laps娱乐公司
原子怪兽影业
制作公司
福波斯
原创译制
蒙太奇字幕组
（异步研究所）
（基洛纳区调查：档案446 — 纳伦·沃恩
1990年6月19日
美国能源部）
Okay, okay, okay, okay...
好 好 好
Okay...
没事的
Yes... Yes...
对 对
Yes, yes, come on... Come on, yes! Yes, yes!
对 对 快点 快点 没错 没错
Okay. Okay. Okay.
到了 到了 到了
Here we go, here we go.
找到了 找到了
Okay. Okay. Fuck.
好 好 该死
Work. Work. Work.
能用 能用 一定得能用
Standard... Okay...
基准组... 好...
Standard, can you- can you hear me?
基准组 你们...你们能收到吗？
This is Naren.
我是纳伦
And I've, um...
我 呃...
I've been separated, uh, from the others.
我跟其他人走散了
And I think I'm okay,
我应该没事
but I'm not sure where I, uh...
我不知道我现在到底在哪儿
I've never been out this far before, so I don't...
我从来没走到过这么深 所以我也...
There was this, uh...
刚才有个...
I didn't get a good look at it, but there was, um...
我没看清 可是 呃...
there's something else in here.
这里还有别的东西
I need you guys.
你们快来
Okay? I need you guys to get me, please.
明白吗？快来接我 求你们了
Fuck, I need you guys to come out and get me.
该死 快来把我弄出去
Can you... can you come, please, standard?
麻烦来接我 求你们了 基准组
Standard?
收到了吗？
Oh, fuck!
完了
Fuck...
Fuck! Fuck...
该死 该死
Oh, shit... What the fuck?
该死 搞什么鬼？
（需无用信...）
What the fuck?
怎么回事？
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
完了 完了 完了
Shit.
该死
Fuck!
完了
Fuck, fuck, fuck! Fuck!
不 不 完了 完了
《后室》
（山脊公寓楼盘）
We all have our loops, our habits...
谁都有自己的死循环 甩不掉的习惯...
...behaviors that keep us walking in circles...
我们总是重蹈覆辙...
...reaching for the same solutions over and over again,
一遍遍地尝试老路
（克船长的家具帝国）
thinking each time they'll take you somewhere new.
却指望能走出一条新路
But they don't.
但没用
And still,
毕竟
it's the neural pathway of least resistance.
神经回路总是走阻力最小的路
（奸商）
A path you made.
你给自己铺了一条小路
It's the one that kept you safe when you were a child.
小时候 这条路保护了你
（全店促销 低价保证 一件不留 全场甩卖）
You learned to push people away
你学会了在被伤害之前
before they could hurt you.
抢先一步把别人推开
And now,
但现在
as an adult,
你成年了
（逾期通知）
you're still stuck right where you started.
你依然留在原地
Alone.
唯独你一人
I mean, I'm not lonely.
我有人陪啊
I have employees and... customers.
我有店员 还有顾客
I didn't say lonely. I said alone.
我没说有人陪 我说的是唯独你一人
Yeah, well, I mean...
好吧 是 但是...
I hurt people.
我老是伤人
I don't want to. It's just the way I'm wired.
我也不想 可我脑回路就是这样接的
So maybe I deserve to be alone.
可能就该把自己关起来
Do you think anyone deserves to be alone?
谁活该把自己关着吗？
I don't know, but, you know,
我说不好 但怎么说呢
maybe it's not such a bad thing.
也许这样也挺好
Being alone feels...
自我封闭...
deeply ingrained.
已经刻进骨子里了
I understand.
我理解
You've had dreams and a lot of resistance,
你有梦想 但老是受挫
not a lot of support in realizing those dreams.
身边也没人支持你
And when we've experienced...
当伤害变成了...
hurt again and again,
一次次家常便饭
we start to expect it.
你就会习惯性地想
It's like, "Oh, I know this path.
“哦 这路我熟”
I know where it goes."
“下场一定是一样的”
So...
所以...
are you interested in forging a new path
你想不想摆脱这个死循环
and see where that leads?
走出一条不同的路？
Sure.
好啊
Why not? You know, I'm here.
我来都来了 就试试吧
Great.
很好
So I want to revisit
要不咱们重温一下...
an exercise we've done before.
之前练过的那个...
The role play.
角色扮演
- Oh, the acting thing? - Yeah.
- 哦 演戏那套？ - 对
- I feel stupid doing that. - I know.
- 我觉得太丢人了 - 我懂
But we have a few minutes. Let's, um...
但既然还有点时间 就....
Yeah, let's try. A little bit.
试一下吧 稍微试试
All right.
好吧
Let's set the scene.
咱们先定个场景
Let's go back to the night that Barbara left you.
回到芭芭拉离开你的那晚
You mean the night she kicked me out of my own house?
你是说她把我从我自己家给撵出去的那晚？
Yeah.
对
I'm playing myself.
我演我自己
And I'll be Barbara.
我演芭芭拉
It is my house, by the way.
别忘了 那可是我的房子
I'm the one paying for it.
房贷都是我在还
- I know. - All right.
- 我知道 - 好吧
Okay, so, um...
好 那...
I got home late. I don't know how late.
那天我回家晚了 具体几点我忘了
Uh... She was already asleep. Maybe midnight.
那时候她已经睡了 应该是半夜了
She usually goes to bed before... It doesn't matter.
她一般睡得早... 算了 这不重要
The point is, I was in the kitchen, and, um...
重点是我当时在厨房 额...
the glass, I broke the glass, and...
有个杯子 我把杯子打碎了
she comes running down to see what happened, and...
她听见动静跑下来 然后...
things escalated.
就闹起来了
And how do you feel?
那你当时什么感受？
Well, I was...
我当时...
I was drunk, and, um...
我当时喝多了...
I-I felt stupid, you know.
我 我觉得自己挺蠢的 你懂吧
I was angry, because... because I broke the glass.
我就火了 因为...因为我把杯子打碎了
Can you say that to me?
你能对着我再说一遍吗？
- Uh, what, to-to Barbara? - Yeah.
- 对着你 对着芭芭拉？ - 对
Um... I'm sorry that I woke you.
对不起 把你吵醒了
Maybe if you'd come home earlier,
要是你能早点回家
we could have spent the evening together.
咱们今晚本该待在一起的
No, I was... I was working, you know?
我 我在加班 你懂的
I came straight home after work.
下班后我就直接回来了
Be honest with me, please.
诚实点吧
I can smell it on your breath.
你身上那酒气我都闻得见
I had a few beers.
我就去喝了一点啤酒
Define a few.
一点是多少？
Well, it was a hard day.
唉 今天太累了
I needed to wind down.
我得喝点放松放松
All you ever do is wind down.
你不成天在放松吗？
You're always at the store.
成天呆在那店里
You want kids, right?
你想要孩子 对吧？
- We both do. - Well, you know...
- 咱们都想要 - 但你要知道...
having a family takes money,
养孩子得花钱
which means someone has to work.
总得有人去挣钱
Unless being a professional student
除非现在当学生
is considered a job these days.
也能算份工作了
That's not fair. You know I had to take time off.
你不能这么说 你知道我得休学一段时间
Well, it's not my fault if you can't keep up.
你自己跟不上 凭什么怪我
How are you going to be a lawyer
连法学院都搞不定
if you can't even handle law school?
还想怎么当律师？
Who do you think pays for everything
当你这个三十岁的“大一新生”
while you're gallivanting around campus
在学校里到处瞎逛时
like a 30-year-old freshman?
也不想想谁在供你上学？
I'll give you a hint: it's me.
提示你一下 那就是我
I pay for your school, I pay for your time off school,
你上学是我供 休学也是我供
I pay for the roof over your head.
连住这儿都还是我在供
- Can I talk now? - No! No.
- 我能说句话吗？ - 不 我还没说完
Because I'd like to know, what do you think happens
我倒想知道 要是你真混到毕业了
if you do manage to graduate?
又会发生什么？
You know, you pop out a kid, then leave me with the bill.
生个娃 然后继续把账单甩给我吗？
Or am I stuck at home changing diapers because
还是你天天忙你的第一份工作
you're too busy working for the first time in your life?
让我在家里给娃换屎尿？
- Now you're being cruel. - I'm being honest.
- 你这话太过分了 - 我只是说实话
I thought that's what you always wanted.
在我看来这就是你的追求
Just because you didn't get to be an architect doesn't mean--
你没考上建筑师 并不代表...
I am a fucking architect!
老子就是建筑师！
God damn it, I'm just stuck selling shit furniture because
我之所以得成天在那破店里卖这些玩意儿
someone won't get off their fat fucking ass and help me!
就是因为某个懒猪在家混吃等死 根本不肯出力
How do you feel, Clark?
克拉克 现在感觉怎么样？
Who am I talking to?
我在跟谁说话呢？
- Me, here, now. - You? Okay.
- 和我 此刻 此地 - 哦 你啊 好吧
Um...
那个...
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to, uh...
对不起 我不是有意说...
...you know, get angry
就是 刚才发火了
or lose my temper or whatever.
情绪失控了那种
I know.
我知道
That's the purpose of the whole exercise.
练习的目的就在这儿
This is a good start.
这是一个不错的开始
To feel what you feel,
正视你的感受
and then learn to identify a new path.
然后慢慢找出一条新路
Your reaction was actually quite normal.
你的反应其实很正常
Well, that's me!
呵呵 我就这德行
Well, ahoy there, mateys!
哟 伙计们 瞧瞧这儿啊！
Tired of spending your hard-earned doubloons on overpriced furniture?
还打算把金币全砸在那些冤大头家具上？
Looking for deals that'll shiver your timbers?
想买惊掉下巴的跳海价吗？
Then come on down to Cap'n Clark's Ottoman Empire,
赶快来克船长的家具帝国！
the Santa Clara Valley's favorite warehouse and showrooms.
圣克拉拉谷的头号家具大卖场
【圣克拉拉谷：位于美国西部】
You'll find bedrooms, living rooms,
卧室 客厅 餐厅 书房 浴室
dinettes, dens and bathrooms aplenty.
全屋家具 应有尽有！
First-time homeowners? We've got ya.
刚买房的？来这儿就对了！
New parents looking for Billy's first crib?
新当爹妈的？
We've got ya!
来这就对了！
From the latest in modern design
时髦现代样样全
to the classic styles of yesteryear,
经典复古通通有
it's all here and it's all a steal.
价格低到没对手
What's that, Polly?
怎么啦 波莉？
You're worried about credit?
信用卡里钱不够？
Ha! Cap'n Clark says no credit, no problem!
哈哈！在克船长这儿 钱不够 没问题！
Sail the high seas of high quality,
快来畅游顶级家具海洋
and leave your money problems at the door.
把钱的问题统统抛在脑后
Walk in today
今天就来店里
and get your dream sectional lounger,
把梦想直接搬回家！
kitchen table, floor lamp, and bed frame here
桌椅板凳 灯具摆件随便挑！
at Cap'n Clark's Ottoman Empire,
克船长的家具帝国
located at Capitol and McKee, just off the 680.
就在680号公路出口 国会路和麦基路口
Arr! Walk in today...
嘿吼！赶紧过来...
...kick your feet back,
翘起二郎腿
and enjoy an empire of your own!
当你的家具大王！
For every sultan deserves a throne,
毕竟 国王得有王座
and we've got one with your name on it,
而你的专属王座 就在这儿等着你
here at Cap'n Clark's--
就在克船长的...
No way!
卧槽
- Clark, you good? - Turn the camera off.
- 克拉克 没事吧？ - 快把相机关了
No, no, it's good. It's outtake stuff, dude.
不不 拍得好 这种花絮才有趣
- Turn the fucking camera off. - Okay... Jesus...
- 赶紧给老子关掉 - 好吧...我的天
You, uh, you need help?
那个 要帮忙吗？
No, I got it, I got it.
不用 我自己来
Um...
那个...
- Are we going again, or...? - No.
- 还要重拍吗？ - 不拍了
Kat, you can open the store now.
小凯 去开门营业吧
We've been open.
早就开了
（全店促销 低价保证 一件不留 全场甩卖）
You know, dude, I still don't get it.
老哥 我还是没搞懂
（结束南非种族隔离）
Are you, like, a pirate or a sultan?
你演的是海盗还是国王？
- Just be good to establish it. - I'm a... Shut up.
- 最好还是明确一下 - 我是个...闭嘴
（结束南非种族隔离）
Piece of cheap particleboard bullshit.
刨花板做的破椅子
Clear this stuff up, will you?
快把这东西弄走 听到没？
Here.
拿着
（全店促销 低价保证 一件不留 全场甩卖）
（1990年6月）
Shit.
该死
Sorry about that.
抱歉
How's it looking?
怎么样 查出来没？
Meter reads fine.
电表没问题
If your bill's coming in high, that's on you.
电费要是高 只能是你自己用得多
What about the outages? That happens after hours.
那跳电的事怎么说 打烊后就出现
Don't know. Fluorescents must be tripping a breaker.
没准是荧光灯出问题 导致跳闸了
I turn the overheads off when the store closes,
但是一打烊我就把顶灯都关了
before the power gets weird.
还没闪之前就关了
Anyway, wouldn't that just make the bills go down?
而且如果真是那样 电费不该更少吗？
Where's your breaker box?
配电箱在哪儿？
I'm no expert,
虽然我不是专家
but I checked earlier, and everything looks okay.
但我之前看过了 没看出什么问题
- You said the lights flicker. - Yeah, the whole store does.
- 你说灯会闪 - 对 整个店都闪
- Huh. - Just not at the same time.
- 是吗？ - 只是不一起闪
One night, I lose the power upstairs.
有一晚是楼上
Next night, it's down here. There's no rhyme or...
下一晚就变成了楼下 完全没规律
Who the hell installed this thing?
谁装的这鬼东西？
Well, the building came wired.
这房子买来时 回路就这样接的
I mean, it's dated, but it's not that old.
虽然有点年头 但也不至于不能用
Take a look at this.
你来看看这个
That wasn't there before.
之前没这东西
Or...
也许...
maybe I didn't notice. Like I say, I'm no expert.
是我没注意到 我不是专家
Why-why is it... why is it going that way?
为...为什么是斜着的？
Better question:
应该问的是
what is it even connected to?
这东西到底连到哪儿了
Huh?
懂吗？
Kat! How's the power?
小凯 楼上灯怎么样？
What?
干嘛？
Anything happen up there?
上面有反应吗？
What the hell?
怎么搞的
The rat's back.
老鼠又来了
- But the power's on. - Yeah.
- 灯还正常吧 - 正常
I thought we killed the rat.
我还以为咱们已经把老鼠给干掉了
We killed  "a"  rat.
咱们才干掉了一只
- So is this the problem? - Don't see how.
- 这就是问题原因吗？ - 没道理啊
Power can't even go through this part of the circuit.
电路根本不走这里
It's just...
它纯粹是...
there.
莫名其妙出现在这
Like some schmo just stuck it in there.
像被哪个笨蛋随便塞进去的
Yeah.
没错
Do you ever feel like you're living behind glass?
你是否觉得生活像被隔在了一层玻璃之后？
Watching life happen,
看着世界在眼前上演
but never really stepping into it?
自己却只能旁观？
Maybe it's time to open the window within.
现在 是时候打开心灵之窗了
You can be the author of your own design
你可以重新定义自己的人生
because we all deserve another chance
我们每个人 都值得拥有另一次机会
to fulfill our dreams.
让梦想重新启航
The moment you believe change is possible,
只要你相信改变是可能的
you've already begun.
你就已经开始了这段旅程
Order The Window Within
立即订购《心灵之窗》
(《心灵之窗》)
and the companion three-part audio program,
以及配套的三辑音频课程
（突破障碍 掌控人生
打破那扇窗）
Guided Openings, by Dr. Mary Klein.
《引导之门》 均由玛丽·克莱因医生倾力呈现
（三辑音频课程）
Available now for $24.95 plus shipping.
现价24.95美元 运费另计
Call 1-800-555-0199.
请拨打1-800-555-0199
（克里斯·弗格森公司出品）
It's never too late to forge a new path.
开辟一条新路 永远不晚
【克里斯·弗格森：《后室》电影制片人】
"So, you're still trusting paper folders,
“你居然还在信任纸质文件夹”
"mislabeled tapes, and a locked filing cabinet
“贴错标签的磁带 还有个谁拿把钥匙”
"that anyone with a spare key can open?"
“都能开的文件柜？”
"Your business runs on information,
“信息决定企业的生死”
"yet most companies treat their data like clutter..."
“但大多数公司却把数据当成了堆杂物...”
That small blip is not an asteroid.
那个信号不是小行星
It's a spaceship, and it's on our tail.
是一艘飞船 它咬住我们了
（1970年圣克鲁斯现代主义建筑设计论坛）
- It's getting closer. - Impossible, Rigna.
- 它在靠近 - 不可能 里格娜
They couldn't have spotted us. We have our radar shield on.
他们不可能发现我们 雷达隐身还开着呢
I know that, sir, but they are gaining on us.
我知道 长官 但他们追上来了
Is it possible Earth has a secret device
难道地球人有某种秘密设备
that can penetrate our radar shield?
能穿透我们的雷达隐身罩？
Piece of shit.
垃圾
"Why did you do this to yourself?"
“为什么 你要这样对待自己？”
"How did you get here?"
“你是怎么来到这里的？”
"Your consciousness is a room full of memories
“你的意识 就像一个装满记忆的房间”
"that is constantly evolving."
“它在时刻重构 在无限演变”
（收音机 磁带）
"But as you walk through life,
“在普通人的生活中”
"the untrained mind can start to build walls,
“不自知的人会开始筑墙”
"put up barriers
“建立屏障”
"to protect itself from the outside world."
“隔绝外界”
"It's a natural response."
“这是本能反应”
"Something we are often unaware of."
“我们常常对此毫无察觉”
"But if gone unchecked,
“但久而久之”
"it can leave you feeling trapped."
“你会发现 自己被囚禁了”
"You can become convinced that the world outside
“你会说服自己”
"is better off without you."
“外面的世界不需要你”
"That you never deserve the relationships you've had."
“你会告诉自己 自己不配被爱”
"Resigned to watch your life unfold
“于是 你只能蜷缩在窗后”
"from behind a lone window."
“当个旁观者 静静地看着生活上演”
"I can help you open it now
“让我来帮你打开”
"because the window isn't locked."
“因为窗户根本没锁”
"The latch was never broken."
“门也没有封死”
"Are you ready to step through?"
“准备好跨过去了吗？”
"So that you can reclaim that which was once yours...
“去夺回属于你的东西”
"and take back control of your life."
“去重新主宰你的生命”
"The life you want to be living."
“去过你想过的人生”
"Unburdened by the traumas of the past."
“卸下过去的重负”
"Free of the confines you had built."
“走出那些你亲手打造的围墙”
...to leave, and so I decided...
...所以我想...
"And free to choose a path of your own design."
“开辟一条属于你自己的路”
（家庭牙科诊所 米莱服饰）
（停）
"Well, hey there, cowboys and cowgirls!"
“嘿 牛仔们 快瞧这边！”
"Are you looking to rustle up the best deals
“想在格兰德河这块地盘”
【格兰德河：位于美国南部】
"this side of the Rio Grande?"
“抢到最便宜的家具吗？”
Prick.
混球
"Well, yeehaw, I say yeehaw!"
“咿吼！快来大韦恩家具店！”
"Here at Big Wayne's, our dining room sets
“买了我们的餐厅套装”
"are gonna make you feel like you just struck gold."
“就跟挖到金矿一样！”
"So don't even think about going anyplace else."
“别去管那些破店”
"Big Wayne's, just look for the golden--"
“认准大韦恩 认准金色招...”
（大韦恩家具店）
What the...
搞什么...
（由此下楼）
Stupid...
该死
Fuck! Piece of shit!
看老子怎么修理你
（亭亻）
（粤语）“各位好吗？祝各位平安健康快乐”
（阿卡德语）“愿一切都很好”
（俄语）“你好 欢迎你们”
（泰语）“远方土地的朋友们 你们好”
（泰语）“在这片土地上的我们 向你们所有人致以诚挚的问候”
（阿拉伯语）“我们向星际中的朋友们致以问候”
（阿拉伯语）“但愿时间能让我们相聚”
（罗马尼亚语）“向大家问好”
（法语）“大家好”
（缅甸语）“你们好吗？”
（希伯来语）“你好”
（西班牙语）“你好 向大家致敬”
（印尼语）“女士们先生们 晚上好”
（印尼语）“再见...”
Hello?
有人吗？
（克丘亚语）“用克丘亚语向你们”
（克丘亚语）“每一个人问好”
（旁遮普语）“欢迎你们”
（赫梯语）“你们好”
（孟加拉语）“你好 愿到处都有和平”
（拉丁语）“无论你们是谁 你们好”
（拉丁语）“我们对你们心怀善意”
（拉丁语）“并带着和平穿梭星际”
（亚兰语）“你好”
（荷兰语）“向每个人致以诚挚的问候”
（德语）“向所有人致以诚挚的问候”
（乌尔都语）“愿和平与你们同在”
（乌尔都语）“我们代表地球的居民”
（乌尔都语）“欢迎你们”
What the fuck?
搞什么鬼？
（越南语）“...致以友好的问候”
（土耳其语）“亲爱的说土耳其语的朋友们”
（土耳其语）“祝你们有个美好的早晨”
（日语）“你好 你们好吗？”
（印地语）“来自地球居民的问候”
（威尔士语）“祝你们现在及未来健康”
（意大利语）“致以最美好的祝愿和问候”
（僧伽罗语）“健康长寿”
（恩古尼语）“向伟大的你们致意”
（恩古尼语）“祝你们永恒繁荣”
（塞索托语）“向伟大的你们致以问候”
（吴语）“祝大家好”
（亚美尼亚语）“向宇宙中存在的...”
（亚美尼亚语）“所有生命致以问候”
（朝鲜语）“你们好”
（波兰语）“欢迎 来自异世界的生命”
（尼泊尔语）“地球人祝愿你们拥有一个和平的未来”
（汉语）“各位都好吧？我们都很想念你们”
（汉语）“有空请到这儿来玩”
（伊拉族语）“祝愿你们一切都好”
（瑞典语）“来自地球...”
（瑞典语）“伊萨卡小镇一名程序员的问候”
（齐切瓦语）“其他星球的朋友们 你们好吗？”
（古加拉特语）“地球人类向宇宙各处”
（古加拉特语）“致以诚挚问候”
（古加拉特语）“期待着收到你们的回复”
（乌克兰语）“来自我们世界的问候”
（乌克兰语）“祝愿你们幸福健康 长久繁荣”
（波斯语）“向遥远天际的....”
（奥里亚语）“来自太阳系第三颗行星...”
（奥里亚语）“地球的问候”
（干达语）“向宇宙所有族群致意”
（干达语）“愿和平永远伴随你们”
（马拉地语）“地球人民向你们传递美好的祝愿”
（台语）“太空的朋友们 你们好”
（台语）“吃过饭没？来我们这儿坐坐”
（异步研究所雇员 纳伦·沃恩）
（匈牙利语）“用匈牙利语向宇宙中所有热爱和平的生命致意”
（泰卢固语）“说泰卢固语的人们...”
Hello?
有人吗？
（捷克语）“亲爱的朋友们 祝你们万事如意”
（卡纳达语）“代表说卡纳达语的人们 向你们致以美好祝愿”
（拉贾斯坦语）“大家好 我们这里很幸福”
（拉贾斯坦语）“愿你们那里也同样幸福”
"Hello from the children of planet Earth."
（英语）“来自地球儿童的问候”
【多国语问候：源自1977年旅行者号金唱片】
（古希腊语）“你们好 无论你们是谁...”
（葡萄牙语）“愿所有人平安幸福”
（粤语）“各位好吗？祝各位平...”
Ooh...
哦...
（克丘亚语）“用克丘亚语向你们”
（克丘亚语）“每一个人问好”
（旁遮普语）“欢迎你们”
（赫梯语）“你们好”
（孟加拉语）“你好 愿到处都有和平”
（拉丁语）“无论你们是谁 你们好”
（拉丁语）“我们对你们心怀善意”
（拉丁语）“并带着和平穿梭星际”
（亚兰语）“你好”
（荷兰语）“向每个人致以诚挚的问候”
（德语）“向所有人致以诚挚的问候”
（乌尔都语）“愿和平与你们同在”
（乌尔都语）“我们代表地球的居民”
（乌尔都语）“欢迎你们”
（越南语）“诚挚地向你们致以友好的问候”
（土耳其语）“亲爱的说土耳其语的朋友们”
（土耳其语）“祝你们有个美好的早晨”
（日语）“你好 你们好吗？”
（印地语）“来自地球居民的问候”
（威尔士语）“祝你们现在及未来健康”
（意大利语）“致以最美好的祝愿和问候”
（僧伽罗语）“健康长寿”
（恩古尼语）“向伟大的你们致意”
（恩古尼语）“祝你们永恒繁荣”
（塞索托语）“向伟大的你们致以问候”
（吴语）“祝大家好”
（亚美尼亚语）“向宇宙中存在的...”
（亚美尼亚语）“所有生命致以问候”
（朝鲜语）“你们好”
（波兰语）“欢迎 来自异世界的生命”
（尼泊尔语）“地球人祝愿你们拥有一个和平的未来”
（汉语）“各位都好吧？我们都很想念你们”
（汉语）“有空请到这儿来玩”
（伊拉族语）“祝愿你们一切都好”
（瑞典语）“来自地球...”
（瑞典语）“伊萨卡小镇一名程序员的问候”
（齐切瓦语）“其他星球的朋友们...”
Anyone there?
是谁啊？
Oh, fuck...
哦 该死...
（亭亻）
Okay, Okay...
好 好
（法语）“大家好”
（缅甸语）“你们好吗？”
（希伯来语）“你好”
（西班牙语）“你好 向大家致敬”
（印尼语）“女士们先生们 晚上好”
（印尼语）“再见期待下次再见”
（克丘亚语）“用克丘亚语向你们”
（克丘亚语）“每一个人问好”
（旁遮普语）“欢迎你们”
（赫梯语）“你们好”
（孟加拉语）“你好 愿到处都有和平”
（拉丁语）“无论你们是谁 你们好”
（拉丁语）“我们对你们心怀善意”
（左声道 右声道）
（拉丁语）“并带着和平穿梭星际”
（亚兰语）“你好”
（基洛纳区-监视点J3 1990年6月29日）
（荷兰语）“向每个人致以诚挚的问候”
（德语）“向所有人致以诚挚的问候”
（乌尔都语）“愿和平与你们同在”
（乌尔都语）“我们代表地球的居民”
（乌尔都语）“欢迎你们”
Sorry I'm late.
抱歉来晚了
Traffic was hell, and I couldn't leave early.
路上堵死了 我又没法提前走
Let's just use the time we have.
没关系 趁还有时间聊聊吧
How are you today, Clark?
今天感觉怎么样 克拉克？
How do I look?
你觉得呢 我看起来怎么样？
Fine. A little tired, maybe.
挺好的 可能有点累吧
I look like shit.
我简直糟糕透了
Can I ask, and there is
我想确认一下
no wrong answer here, you know that...
放心回答 没什么对错
Are you intoxicated right now?
你现在是不是有一点喝醉了？
Why you say it like that?
你干嘛这么问？
Like what?
怎么问了？
I haven't had a drink since Friday.
我从周五起就没碰过一滴酒
It's probably why I look like shit.
没准儿我这副鬼样子就是因为没喝酒
- Can I ask you something? - Sure.
- 我能问你个事吗？ - 请说
You ever 5150'd someone?
你把人强制关精神病院过吗？
【加州法律5150条：强制将危险精神病人送院观察】
A few times over the years, when it was necessary.
这么多年确实有过几次 只要情况需要
Wh-wha-what makes it necessary?
那...那...那什么样的情况才算需要？
If I believe that the person is a danger to themselves or others,
只要我认为对方有伤人自残的风险
or they're gravely disabled.
或者无法自理
Okay.
行
Um...
那个...
I found something in the store.
我在店里有了点发现
Okay. What did you find?
好 发现了什么？
Uh...
呃...
A place. I f...
是个地方 我...
I found a place.
我发现了个地方
A place?
地方？
Yeah. It's like, um...
嗯 感觉...
It's like the store just, uh...
感觉店就那样...
continues, I guess.
往外扩了
It's like... you know, like there's a wall
你知道吧...店有墙
and on the other side of the wall,
墙后头居然还是店
the store just keeps going, you know,
没完没了地往外扩
like-like a... like a copy of itself.
就像 就像 像个克隆的
I-I-I figure they're using mirrors or something
我...我猜入口是用镜子什么的给挡住的
to hide the entrance, I don't know.
我不确定
Sorry, I'm not following you.
不好意思 我没听明白
Is this a room you didn't know about before?
你是说找到了个之前没发现的房间？
No.
不是
Okay, so y-y-you go in and, uh...
就是...就是你一进去后
at first it just looks like a- like an office building.
看着像个...像个写字楼
Like a... like a huge office building, you know?
一个巨大的办公室 你懂吧？
And then, uh... But then you-you keep going,
然后...你 你继续往里走
and then-then you realize
接着...接着你就发现
th-th-that none of it makes any sense.
所...所有东西都不对劲
It's-it's like, um... Imagine describing a dog
怎..怎么说呢...想象一下
to someone who's never seen one before
你给个没见过狗的人形容狗
and then asking them to draw it.
然后让那人把狗画出来
They might get some things right, you know,
可能会画对几个地方
but there's no way they'd get everything right.
但绝不可能全画对
You know, the devil's in the details.
你知道 诡异的在于细节
So from a distance, you look at it,
所以远看像只狗
you think you're seeing a dog, but then you look clos--
但凑近一看...
Why are you looking at me like that?
干嘛那样看我？
I'm just trying to understand.
我只是在试着理解
Oh.
呵
You know, for a shrink, you got a terrible poker face.
你不像个心理医生 怎么表情都写在脸上
What you're saying might sound fantastical,
你说的这些听起来很离奇
but not dangerous.
但并不危险
Are there any people in these offices?
那些办公室里有人吗？
Not that I've seen. You know, I hear, um...
没见过 但我能听到
There's footsteps, an-an-and stuff gets moved around
听到脚步声 而且...而且我一转眼
when I'm not looking.
东西就被挪了位置
I know how this sounds, but you've got to understand,
我知道这听起来很离谱 但你得明白
it's massive in there.
那地方太大了
Like New-York's-subway-system massive, you know.
简直像纽约地铁那么大 懂吧
For all I know, there's hundreds of people.
没准儿里面有好几百人
I just haven't seen them.
我只是没看到
Look.
看
You see? It's like a...
你看 这就像个...
It's like a maze.
就像个迷宫
It just goes on and on and on.
根本没完没了 看不到尽头
Sometimes I'm scared I'll get lost.
我有时候真怕自己会迷路
Why do you think no one else has found this place?
那为什么除了你 没人发现这地方？
I don't know.
我哪知道
The entrance is on the subfloor,
但入口在负一层
so the whole structure is probably underground, you know?
所以整个结构估计都在地下 懂吧
It's not on any city maps.
地图上根本没这个地方
The entrances are hidden, so who'd think to look?
入口根本看不出来 谁会想到去找？
I'm not saying I don't believe you...
我没说不信你...
but you told me yourself
不过 你跟我说
you haven't had a drink since Friday.
你周五就开始戒酒了
- Do you think there is a-- - Okay.
- 这会不会导致幻... - 行了
【译注：戒断反应可能产生幻觉】
- Clark-- - No, no.
- 克拉克 - 停 停
- If this is true-- - Yeah, I get it. Thank you.
- 如果这是真的... - 行 我懂了 多谢您啊
You know, I'm gonna come back here with proof
我迟早会带着证据回来
and you're gonna owe me a serious fucking apology.
到时候你得给我好好道歉
Kat!
小凯
Jesus, goddamn, I'm coming! I'm coming!
那么早谁呀 来了 来了
- Hey. - Cap'n Clark?
- 嘿 - 克船长？
- Um... - Wait, wait, wait, wait. Kat?
- 额... - 等等 等等 小凯 快来
- I'm coming. - Kat!
- 我来了 - 快点
Okay, I'm coming!
行了 我来了
- Look-- -What the fuck?
- 是这样的... - 搞什么鬼
Yeah, I'm sorry, uh...
抱歉 那个...
What are you guys doing tomorrow?
你们明天有空吗？
What are you talking about?
你在说什么呢？
I'll pay you. Two hours. Overtime. Tops.
我给钱 算加班 顶多两个小时 很快的
Okay, pay us for what?
行 给钱干什么？
Research.
做调研
You got the camera, right?
摄像机还在你们那儿吧？
You can-you can borrow it again...
你们能...能再帮我拍点东西吗？
Right?
行不行？
Okay, we are rolling.
好了 开始拍了
We got, um, some shit over here.
这儿摆了些东西
（亭亻）
We got some stop signs
还有停车牌
and, uh... a rope.
还有 呃 绳子
What's the rope for?
拿绳子干嘛？
Supplies.
装备
Oh, great, he's gonna tie us up.
呵呵 看来咱们要被他绑了
No, we're gonna tie ourselves up.
不是我绑 是要给自己绑好
Hmm. Kinky.
唔 挺重口味的
What the fuck?
你胡说什么
Uh, you still haven't told us
呃 你还没说清楚
what we're doing here, man.
我们来这儿干嘛？
I did tell you. Research.
我说了 做调研
These are supplies, and we're using them for research.
这些是调研装备
It's not that hard to understand.
没那么难理解吧
Okay, research for what?
行 研究什么？
Y-you gotta be more specific, dude.
你得具体点 老哥
I'm gonna go through the door.
我要进门了
What door?
什么门？
That's the door.
这就是门
I taped an outline on the other side, too,
我在另一边也贴了框
just to help us find our way back.
以防咱们找不到
- Bobby? - What?
- 阿博？ - 怎么了？
Look, I know it sounds crazy, but follow my lead.
听着 我知道这很离谱 但得听我的
Okay?
懂吗？
I want to be back before sunup.
我想在天亮前赶回来
Dude, it's like 9 p.m. What the fuck are you talk--
老哥 现在才晚上九点 你说什么...
- What the fuck! Clark?! - What the fuck?
- 什么情况 克拉克 - 卧槽
- How did you do that? - Dude, did you...
- 怎么做到的？ - 老哥 你...
Did you fucking see that?! H-how did he, um...
你也看到了吧？他怎...怎么会...
I'm right here. Come see for yourself.
我就在这儿 快进来看看
What the fuck? D-did you just fucking...
搞什么鬼 你居...居然真的...
What? How the f...
什么？怎么会...
Bobby, stop. What are you doing?
你干嘛呢？阿博 快住手
- What the fuck?! - Clark, where are you?
- 卧槽 - 克拉克 你在哪儿？
Ha! Hey, did you... did you see that?
哈哈 你...你看到了没？
- Where the fuck did he go? - Yes, Bobby, I saw it!
- 他钻哪去了？ - 看到了 阿博 我看到了
Oh! Where the f--
我去 搞什...
Just step through the door, you'll be fine!
踏进来就行 没事的
What?! No! Tell us what is going on!
疯了吧 你得先解释清楚
You know what, just...
管他呢 直接...
No, Bobby, wait! Bobby! Wait, what are you doing?
不 阿博 别进去 阿博 快停下 你要干什么？
Bobby!
阿博
What the fuck?!
我去啊
Dude!
老哥
Dude, how is this possible?
老哥 这怎么可能？
- Bobby! Clark! - Okay...
- 阿博 克拉克 - 行...
Where are you? What the fuck is back there?
你们在哪？里面到底是什么地方？
No, no, no, Kat, it's good, it's good.
没事没事 小凯 没事的
J-just, you gotta come see this.
赶紧...赶紧进来看看
I mean... Right, you see...
我是说...对 你看...
You see, it's, um...
你看这 呃...
- It's fine. - Clark, what is this?
- 没问题 - 克拉克 这是什么地方？
- Where are we? - Oh!
- 我们在哪？ - 哦
That's what I'm trying to figure out.
我也正想弄明白呢
Whose, um... Whose shit is this?
这...这是谁的破烂？
Is it-is it... is it part of your store?
是你...是你店里的吗？
If it belongs to someone,
如果真有主人的话
- I haven't met them yet. - Okay...
- 我还没碰到那个人 - 好吧
I've been in here every night since I found the place,
自从发现这地方 我每晚都来
and I still barely scratched the surface.
但也就看了个冰山一角
Come on. I'll show you.
走 我带你们看看
It only gets better.
越往后越有意思
- What the fuck... - Hey. Hey.
- 真扯... - 嘿 嘿
You don't think he, like, dosed us or something, do you?
他别给咱们下药了吧？
What? No, no, no. We're not on drugs.
药？没那回事 咱们没嗑药
I think I'd be able to tell if I was high.
要是嗨了 我肯定能感觉到
You are high!
你现在就嗨着呢
Pot doesn't count.
哈草不算
So, um, it's like...
所以...这就像...
what, like an empty office building?
像个空办公区？
In here? Sure. But it's like it was made
在这儿？算是吧 但这地方简直像是
by a bunch of construction workers on acid.
一帮嗑嗨了的建筑工盖出来的
There's even a pool!
居然还搞了个泳池
There's a pool?
有泳池？
Yeah. I mean, kind of.
没错 算是吧
Keep up.
快跟上
（亭亻）
"Pots." What the fuck?
倒着的“停”什么鬼？
Yeah, no, no, that's the way I went last time.
不不不 那是我上次走的路
Yeah, when I was looking for a staircase down or something.
当时我想找个楼梯下去什么的
Only thing I found so far is basically more of a...
结果只发现了个...
Okay...
好的...
I don't know, it's like a ramp, really.
怎么说呢 其实就是个斜坡
It's, uh... It's up here.
就在这儿...就在前面
We'll be at it in a minute.
马上就到了
Okay...
好吧
How many floors does it go down?
这下面总共有多少层？
Is this not technically...
怎么能挖...
Okay. All right, you filming?
行了 开始拍了吗？
- Yeah. - All right.
- 拍了  - 行
I don't see why Bobby has to be the one to go.
为什么非得让阿博下去？
- I want to. - He's the one with the camera.
- 我想去 - 摄像机在他手上
Well, it's not like it's attached.
相机又没长在他身上
Yeah, well, I mean, to my student ID, yeah, it kinda is.
它挂在我学生证上的 所以就算长在身上了
Any trouble, just give a tug, and I'll pull you up, okay?
要是觉得不对劲 就拽一下 我把你拉上来 明白吧？
Trouble? Clark, what fucking trouble?
不对劲？克拉克 下面有什么不对劲？
There's not going to be any trouble.
不会有事的
Babe, babe, babe, it's good.
宝贝 宝贝 没事
- No, hey-- - It's good. I'm good.
- 别下... - 真的没事 我没问题
Baby, you don't have to do this.
亲爱的 你不用下去
No, it's cool. I-I just want to see what's down there.
没事 我就是想看看下面有什么
- Are you not curious? - This is stupid!
- 你不好奇吗？ - 简直是疯了
- Just go as far as you can. - No, look, look, look!
- 能走多远就走多远 - 没事 你看 你看
You can basically walk down without a rope.
其实不用绳子也能走下去
It's fine, and it's not even steep.
没什么 一点也不陡
Okay.
行吧
Okay, just don't... just one thing.
好 但有一件事
If I don't come back, you'll tell my mom I love her, right?
万一我回不来 记得告诉我妈我爱她哦
- Okay. - All right, okay.
- 行 - 那么 走吧
All right, just take it slow.
好 慢慢来
Okay.
行
Oh, it is actually kind of steep.
哦 实际上还挺陡的
- You good? - Yeah.
- 没问题吧？ - 没问题
- Just, uh... try not to drop me. - All right.
- 拉紧点 别把我摔了 - 放心
Tell me how much you need.
要放绳子告诉我
Whoa... Careful!
喔...慢点
What the... Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! Fuck! Aah...
搞什么...喔 喔 喔 操 啊
What the fuck are you guys doing up there?
你会不会放绳子
Sorry, sorry!
对不起 对不起
It was stuck around the leg of the bed!
绳子绕到床腿上了
- Are you okay? - Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine.
- 你没事吧？ - 行 没事
Jesus fucking Christ...
真是绝了
Just keep letting me down!
继续放绳子
All right. Here we go.
好的 来了
Okay, I'm in.
好了 我下来了
See anything?
看到什么没？
Ugh...
呃...
Uh, it's just...
呃 就是...
It's a bunch of laundry and shit.
就是一堆脏衣服和垃圾
What do you mean? Clothes?
什么意思？衣服？
Yeah, it just fucking stinks down here.
对 这下面真是臭死了
See anything else?
还有什么吗？
Yeah, just, uh... Just give me a minute.
有 呃...给我点时间
Okay.
好的
Oh, god...
真乱
（结束南非种族隔离）
What the fuck?
还撞衫了？
Bobby?
阿博？
Yeah.
怎么了
Just checking that you're okay.
就想确认下你没事
Yeah, I'm fine. Just, um...
嗯 我没事 只是 呃...
Okay...
好吧
Yeah.
嗯
Okay.
没问题
What the fuck...?
搞什么鬼？
Bobby? Come back up!
阿博？快上来
I don't like this!
我心里发毛
Hey! Uh... Let some more line out!
嘿 呃...再多放点绳子
I can't! It's as far as it goes.
不行 已经到头了
Fuck...
该死
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
卧槽 卧槽 卧槽
Pull me up! Pull me up! Pull me up!
快拉我上去 拉我上去 快
Bobby! What is it?
阿博 怎么了？
- Fuck! - What do you see?
- 操 - 你看到了什么？
What the fuck is it? Pull him up!
磨蹭什么 快把他拉上来
- I am! Jesus Christ! - Fuck!
- 我在拉啊 我的天 - 操
Pull harder!
拉快点
Pull, man! What the fuck!
快拉 老哥 搞什么鬼
- It's getting caught on my feet! - Fuck!
- 绳子绕到我脚上了 - 操
- I can't pull-- - Fucking pull harder!
- 绳子绕到... - 快点使劲拉
Clark, hurry up!
克拉克 快点拉
Almost here! Almost here, babe, just a little more!
快到了 快到了 宝贝 坚持住
- Pull him up! - What did you see?
- 快把他拉上来 - 你看到了什么？
- There's, uh, there's someone down there. - We've got you--
- 下...下面有人 - 你安全了...
- What? - Fuck.
- 什么？- 操
Slow down, just breathe. Baby, it's okay.
慢点说 深呼吸 宝贝 没事了
Just get this shit off me, man. Fuck. Jesus.
快把这破玩意儿给我解开 操 真是够了
- It's okay. It's okay. Here. - What did you see?
- 没事了 没事了 来 - 你看到了什么？
- Hey, deep breath. - What kind of knot is this?
- 深呼吸 - 这打的什么破结？
- What the fuck?! - Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- 卧槽 - 哎 哎 哎
- Help us! Clark! - Hold on!
- 快救命 克拉克 - 抓紧我
- Okay, okay, okay! - Help, you fucking asshole!
- 来了 来了 来了 - 救人啊 你个混蛋
- Let me get it! - Untie me, man!
- 让我解 - 快给我解开 老哥
What the hell are you doing, Clark?
克拉克 你特么在磨蹭什么？
- I can't! - Hurry, Clark!
- 我解不开 - 快点 克拉克
- I'm trying, I'm trying! - FUCK!
- 我在弄了 我在弄了 - 操
Don't let go! Don't let go!
别松手 别松手
- Hold on! - Fuck! Don't let me go!
- 坚持住 - 操 千万别放手
- Don't let me go! - Let me get at--
- 千万别放手 - 我去拿...
BOBBY!
阿博！
NO! KAT, NO!
不 小凯 不
Bobby!
阿博
BOBBY!
阿博！
Bobby!
阿博
What are we doing? We need to... Clark!
怎么回事 我们得...克拉克
Bobby! No! No! No!
阿博 别 别 别
Ow... KAT! Kat...
别 小凯 小凯
Bobby!
阿博
Bobby! No!
阿博 不
Kat!
小凯
Oh, fuck...
哦 该死
Oh, no, no, no, no, no! No!
哦 不 不 不 不 不 不
Kat?!
小凯？
Kat?
Hello?
有人吗？
Stay back! Get away from me!
别过来 滚开
（麦基路）
Clark? CLARK!
克拉克？克拉克
I'm here...
我在这儿...
I'm here! It's gonna come back.
就在这 那东西要回来了
Please, Clark, please let me in!
快让我进去 克拉克 求你让我进去
- Kat? - Let me in!
- 小凯？ - 让我进去
Wh-wh-where are you?
你...你在在哪？
We have to go now, Clark! We have to go.
我们得赶紧走 克拉克 没时间了
- It's gonna come back, it's gonna find me! - Kat! Kat? Uh...
- 那东西要回来了 它会找到我的 - 小凯 小凯？额...
Wait, I don't understand. Wh-where are you?
等等 我没搞明白 你到底在哪？
Please, let me the fuck in!
求你了 赶紧让我进去
But it's a... it's-it's a wall!
但这...这是堵墙啊
How can-how can you see me?
你怎么能看到我？
I'm on the other side of the glass.
我在玻璃的另一边
How can you not see me?
你怎么看不见我？
What glass?! What the fuck are you talking about?
什么玻璃？你在说什么鬼话？
Wh-what are you talk--
你在...在说什...？
Okay, can you see anything on your side?
好吧 你那边能看到什么吗？
Can you see a handle, a door? Is there a hatch, anything?
有门把手吗 还是有门？有没有入口之类的东西？
No, no, no, no...
没有 没有 没有...
Uh... Okay. Let me figure this out, okay? Just hold on.
呃...好吧 让我想想办法 好吗？等一下
Hold on, okay? It's just...
坚持住 行吗？只是...
- Clark? - No, no, just let me...
- 克拉克？ - 别急 别急 让我试...
- Clark! - Just hold on!
- 克拉克 - 别急
- Let me figure this out! - CLARK!
- 我找找看 - 克拉克！
- Let me figure this out... - Clark! Clark!
- 别催我 我在想办法 - 克拉克 快跑
Clark, behind you!
克拉克 它就在你身后
（诺拉·克莱...
氯丙...）
【氯丙嗪：抗精神病药物】
Mary!
玛丽 住手
Mary...
玛丽
what were you thinking?
你疯了吗？
I never, ever,
我说过绝对 绝对
ever said you could go outside.
绝对不能出门
It's no good.
绝对不行
They're all over the place.
外面到处都是
"Hi, you've reached Dr. Mary Klein."
“您拨打的是玛丽·克莱因医生的电话”
"I'm not able to answer the call,
“我目前不便接听”
"so please leave a message,
“请留言”
"and I'll get back to you as soon as I can."
“我会尽快给您回电”
"Mary...
“玛丽...”
"I opened the window."
“我打开那扇窗了”
"I won't be coming back."
“我不会再回来了”
（克船长的家具帝国）
"...Please!"
“...求你了”
"Save us!"
“救救我们”
（1983年 异步研究所获得120万美元联邦资助开发下一代核磁共振设备）
"All right! I'll do it!
“好 我照做”
I'll save you! I will do it!"
“我会救你们 我会照做”
"Moon Child!"
“梦翠儿！”
【电影《大魔域》1984：讲述一个男孩通过想象力重建世界的奇幻故事】
I don't know where that hand's been.
谁知道你手之前碰过什么
【《大魔域》英文片名：直译为“永不结束的故事”】
"Well, ahoy there, mateys!"
“哟 伙计们 瞧瞧这儿啊！”
"Now, according to me map,
“按照这藏宝图”
"we've landed on the crystal shores of a bountiful land,
“咱们现在已经登上了这片宝地”
"a land filled with great deals."
“这里的折扣简直是在倒贴啊！”
"So drop your anchors and come on down
“你也赶紧赶紧抛锚靠岸！”
（圣克拉拉谷最低价
地址国会路与麦基路口）
"to Cap'n Clark's Ottoman Empire."
“快来克船长的家具帝国！”
"Get lost in an endless sea
“潜入这顶级家具的海洋吧”
"of quality tables, chairs, couches, and bedroom sets."
“桌椅沙发 卧室全套 样样齐全！”
（地址国会路与麦基路口）
"Need bed bunks for the scallywagses quarters?
“想给小海盗们配上下铺？”
"W've got it all!"
“来这儿就对了！”
"And at prices so low
“价格低到...”
"you'll think that yo're robbing me!"
“你都觉得在抢我的钱啊！”
Hello?
有人吗？
（全店促销 低价保证 一件不留 全场甩卖）
Hello?
有人吗？
（全店促销 低价保证 一件不留 全场甩卖）
Clark?
克拉克？
（无需信用卡）
Clark, can you hear me?
克拉克 你在哪儿？
（由此下楼）
Clark?
克拉克？
（亭亻）
（门 和 家具店）
Clark?
克拉克？
（平面图又变了 屋顶不对 屋顶绝对不对）
（这图纸是谁签的名？但这笔迹 像我的）
（管他的什么超自然 理智点吧）
（此刻和此地是相通的）
Clark?
克拉克？
You found it.
你总算发现了
Why are you hiding?
你怎么不出来？
You were being too loud.
你太刺耳了
Where are we?
我们在哪？
It's...
这里...
...every place that ever was.
是所有存在过的地方
How long have you been here?
你在这儿多久了？
What was that?
什么声音？
Stay calm.
别紧张
It's only me.
这里只有我
You know me.
你了解我
I'm sorry.
抱歉了
This is for your own good.
这全是为你好
As you walk through life,
你说过 在普通人的生活中
the untrained mind accumulates loops, habits...
不自知的人总会走入死循环 养成甩不掉的习惯
...behaviors that keep you drifting in circles,
重蹈覆辙
creating the same problems,
面对相同的问题
reaching for the same solutions
却还是一遍遍地
over and over again.
尝试老路
Still, it's the neural pathway of least resistance.
毕竟 神经回路总是走阻力最小的路
The one I made.
可我的路 是我亲手铺的
The one that kept me safe...
小时候
when I was a child.
这条路保护了我
You know...
你知道...
I learned to push people away before they could hurt me.
我学会了在被伤害之前 抢先一步把别人推开
And, now, as an adult,
而现在 我成年了
I'm still stuck right where I started.
我依然留在原地
Alone.
唯我一人
What is this?
怎么回事？
It's a real mess. Am I right?
真是一团糟 对吧？
Clark...
克拉克...
...let me help you...
让我来帮你...
before you do anything you can't take back.
在你做出无法挽回的事之前
Answer the question.
回答我的问题
Yes, it's a real mess.
是的 真是一团糟
But also beautiful in a way.
但从某种角度看 也很美
No?
不是吗？
Who are these people?
这些人是谁？
This place builds them.
这地方造了他们
Oh, actually, more like it remembers them.
哦 其实更像是在记得他们
And the more times it remembers something,
只不过记得越多
the less it does.
就越走样
Somewhere out there is a guy in a striped shirt,
这个在外面是个穿条纹衫的家伙
but, in here, he's...
但在这儿...
remembered.
他被记成了这样
Just slightly wrong.
有点走样
Somewhere out there is a man
这个在外面是个...
in a wheelchair, and a lamp.
坐轮椅的家伙 带了盏灯
I'm pretty sure that's how you get all of this.
我敢说 这里就是这么回事
You know, all these places
所有这些地方啊
and rooms and buildings
房间和建筑啊
misremembering themselves.
全都记岔了
Clark...
克拉克...
let's talk this through.
我们好好谈谈吧
In some ways...
换个角度看...
they're an improvement on the originals.
他们甚至比原件更好
For starters,
比如...
they can't feel anything.
他们没有任何感觉
Can you imagine how good that must feel?
想象一下 那样得有多自在啊
I mean...
我是说...
...there's no thoughts or pain, no ego...
没念头 没痛苦 没自我...
...no fear.
也没恐惧
They simply...
纯粹就是...
exist.
在那儿
Like... like furniture!
就像...就像家具一样
Look at this. The best part.
看这儿 最绝的来了
You can eat them!
他们能吃
That's my, uh...
这是我的 呃...
assistant manager.
助理
I tried to help her, but she just, uh...
我想帮她 但她就是...
Clark!
克拉克
If you untie me, we can talk this through,
你把我解开 我们可以聊聊
get you feeling better.
让你心里好受点
Yeah, well, what if I did untie you?
是吗 就算解开了
You know, what then?
那又怎样？
You'd run around here
你顶多像个
like a chicken with its head cut off,
没头苍蝇一样到处乱窜
looking for a way out.
找你的出口
But you'd end up in the same place you are now.
但你最后还是得回到这儿
Like the path thing you're always talking about.
就跟你爱说的那套路径理论一样
Clark!
克拉克
I just want to help you. Just tell me what you need.
我是真的想帮你 只要告诉我你想要什么
I'll-I'll-I'll do it.
我...我...我一定照做
Yeah?
是吗？
Yeah. Yes, please.
是的 是的 拜托了
Okay.
行
Well, I want you to tell me
我想听你亲口说
that I didn't do anything wrong, you know,
我没做错任何事
that-that you were wrong about me.
是你之前对我看走眼了
I was wrong about you! I was.
是我看走眼了 是我错了
- I was wrong about you. - No, no, not-not like that.
- 我真的看错你了 - 不 不 不要这样
Not... not so fast, okay?
别 别这么快 好吗？
I mean, I wanna... I want to set the scene first!
我的意思是 我想...我想先定个场景
Let's start, um...
咱们从...
well, the night that, uh...
嗯...从那晚开始
that I got kicked out of my own house.
就是我被撵出我自己家的那晚
Yeah?
怎么样？
It was, um... It was late.
那天 嗯...很晚了
A lot darker.
屋里很暗
Uh...
呃...
Lights, please.
关下灯
I tried this exercise with her before.
之前跟她试过
It doesn't go anywhere.
她根本不会动 结果都一样
Fine!
行
I'll do it myself.
我自己来
It's still my house after all.
毕竟 这终究还是我的房子
Yeah.
好了
Thank you. Much better.
谢谢 这样才对
But there's...
不过...
still...
还是...
something off.
缺点儿什么
Clark, please...
克拉克 求你..
No, please, don't, don't...!
不 拜托 不要 不要...
I'm sorry.
对不起
I'm sorry, I...
对不起 我...
broke the glass and woke you up.
把杯子打碎了 还把你吵醒了
I know how you like to sleep early.
我知道你睡得早
I was at the store late.
我在店里忙太久了
I guess I lost track of the time.
就忘了时间
I was checking inventory.
我之前在对账
But...
然后...
I stopped off for a few beers.
顺路去喝了一点啤酒
- Clark-- - Barbara!
- 克拉克 - 芭芭拉
I was checking inventory.
我之前在对账
Then I stopped off for a few beers.
然后顺路去喝了一点啤酒
Defi-define a few.
一点...一点是多少？
As many as I wanted.
我想喝多少就喝多少
Because this is my house.
因为这房子是我的
I pay for it.
房贷都是我在还
I pay for everything. I pay for you to go to school.
所有的钱都是我在出 你上学是我供
I pay for your time off school!
休学也是我供
I pay for the roof over your head!
连住这儿都是我在供
You want kids, right?
你想要孩子 对吧？
Well, that takes money.
养孩子得花钱
So someone has to work around here.
总得有人去挣钱
I said someone has
我说过了这儿得有人干活
to get off her fat ass and work around here!
不能在那儿当个懒猪混吃等死
Just because you didn't get to be an architect don--
你没考上建筑师 并不代表...
I am a fucking architect.
老子就是建筑师
I'm just stuck selling shit furniture because someone
我之所以得成天在那破店里卖这些玩意儿
won't get off her fat fucking ass and help me!
就是因为某个懒猪在家混吃等死 根本不肯出力！
- I'm not your wife! - Stay in character.
- 我才不是你老婆 - 别出戏
Stay in character!
继续演
- I've never even met her! - STAY IN CHARACTER!
- 我压根就没见过她 - 继续演你的角色
FUCK YOU!
滚你妈的蛋！
What did you say?
你说什么？
You wanna know the real reason your wife left you?
你想知道为什么你老婆甩了你吗？
It wasn't the drinking,
根本不是因为酗酒
or the stumbling home at all hours, or the rage.
不是半夜烂醉回家 甚至不是你的坏脾气
It was the whining!
是因为你是个巨婴
Nothing's ever your fault, is it?
你这辈子没一件事是你的错 对吧？
You drink too much? Blame your job.
喝多了 赖工作
You hate your job? Blame the world.
恨职业 赖世界
You get kicked out of the house?
被撵出家门
Blame your wife.
赖老婆
You attack me and tie me up?
现在你攻击我 绑架我
Blame your brain!
居然还敢赖在脑子上
You are your fucking brain, you dipshit!
你这颗烂脑子 就是你本人 废物
- You're saying it's my fault? - Yes!
- 所以 全都是我的错？ - 是啊
But it's just the way you're wired, isn't it?
但你肯定又要赖你的脑回路 对吧？
ISN'T IT?!
对不对！
How do I stop doing that?
那我怎么才能停下来？
Honestly, I have no fucking idea.
实话实说 我一丁点的招都没有了
I can't help you, Clark.
我帮不了你 克拉克
As much as I tried.
能试的我都试了
It's just not up to me.
这根本不是我能左右的
I can't save anyone.
我谁也救不了
You know...
你知道吗？
I don't think I want to change.
我其实不想改
Then don't.
那就别改
I like it in here.
我喜欢这里
For the first time in a long time,
这么久以来
I feel like I'm...
我第一次觉得...
like I'm right where I'm supposed to be.
我终于找到了我的归宿
Then stay.
那就留下吧
Right where you are.
就这么待着
But let me go.
但你得放我走
I'm sorry.
对不起
About what?
对不起什么？
What are you doing in here?
你来这儿干什么？
This is Mary.
这是玛丽
She's our therapist.
她是咱们的心理治疗师
She was just leaving.
她正要离开
No, no.
不 不
You don't have to worry.
你不用担心
She says we don't need to change.
她说咱们不需要改变
It's okay.
没关系的
It's just the way we're wired.
咱们的脑回路就是这样接的
（由此下楼）
（干达语）“向宇宙所有族群致意”
（干达语）“愿和平永远伴随你们”
（马拉地语）“地球人民向你们传递美好的祝愿”
（一件不留 全场甩卖）
（台语）“太空的朋友们 你们好”
（台语）“吃过饭没？来我们这儿坐坐”
No...
不
（出口）
（捷克语）“亲爱的朋友们 祝你们万事如意”
（卡纳达语）“代表说卡纳达语的人们 向你们致以美好祝愿”
（拉贾斯坦语）“大家好 我们这里很幸福”
（拉贾斯坦语）“愿你们那里也同样幸福”
"Hello from the children of planet Earth."
（英语）“来自地球儿童的问候”
（古希腊语）“你们好 无论你们是谁 我们带着友谊 拜访朋友”
（葡萄牙语）“愿所有人平安幸福”
（阿卡德语）“愿一切都很好”
（俄语）“你好 欢迎你们”
（泰语）“远方土地的朋友们 你们好...”
（法语）“大家好”
Are you okay? Are you okay?
你没事吧？没事吧？
Who the fuck is that?
这女人是谁？
Who is it?
你是谁？
What happened?
怎么回事？
What about the pirate? Can you still see the pirate?
海盗呢？还在附近吗？
And the other guys? Still going out the back?
其他人呢？他们还在后撤吗？
（塞尔维亚语）“来自我们星球的诚挚祝愿”
（奥里亚语）“来自太阳系第三颗行星”
（奥里亚语）“地球的问候”
（干达语）“向宇宙所有族群致意”
（干达语）“愿和平永远伴随你们”
（马拉地语）“地球人民向你们传递美好的祝愿”
（台语）“太空的朋友们 你们好”
（台语）“吃过饭没？来我们这儿坐坐”
（匈牙利语）“用匈牙利语向宇宙中所有热爱和平的生命致意”
（泰卢固语）“说泰卢固语的人们向你们致以美好的祝愿”
（捷克语）“亲爱的朋友们 祝你们万事如意”
（卡纳达语）“代表说卡纳达语的人们 向你们致以美好祝愿”
（拉贾斯坦语）“大家好 我们这里很幸福”
（拉贾斯坦语）“愿你们那里也同样幸福”
"Hello from the children of planet Earth."
（英语）“来自地球儿童的问候”
Hello, my name is Phil.
你好 我叫菲尔
And you're Mary, yeah?
你是玛丽 对吧？
Uh... I was hoping to ask you a few questions, just for...
我想问你几个问题 主要是...
some clarification on our end,
为了核实一些细节
if that's okay.
没问题吧？
Uh, first thing, um...
呃 首先...
could you establish how you, uh...
你能说说 你是怎么...
got in here?
进来的吗？
I walked through a wall
我穿过了一堵墙
in the basement of a furniture store.
就在一家家具店的地下室里
Can you confirm that this is the location in question?
你看这张照片 是这里吧？
（克船长的家具帝国）
Okay, good. So you were shopping, or...
好的 你当时想购物 还是...
I was looking for someone.
我当时在找人
Um...
呃...
were you looking for this man,
你找的那个人
right here?
是他吧？
Where am I right now?
我现在在哪？
Could you just confirm for me?
帮我确认一下行吗？
Is this man right here the man you were looking for?
这就是你要找的人吧？
Please.
拜托
- Sorry, what was your name? - Phil.
- 抱歉 你刚才说你叫什么？ - 菲尔
Please, Phil. Where am I?
请告诉我 菲尔 我现在在哪？
I'm not...
我不...
I make, um... Sorry, my...
我是做...呃...抱歉 我的...
Our company, we make...
我们的公司 是生产...
MRI machines.
核磁共振成像仪的
（异步研究所）
Or... I should say, um,
或者...应该说
we used to make MRI machines.
我们曾经是做核磁共振仪的
Not anymore.
现在不再做了
That was before we...
那是在我们...
- Before we found-- - You've been there.
- 在我们发现那个.... - 你也进去过
Yes, I have.
是的 我去过
And now, it's my job.
现在这成了我的工作
Every day, I-I go in there
我每...每天都进去
and I just try to f...
试着...
try to find out ev-even a little bit more.
试着多弄懂一点也好
I-I map out areas to the best of my ability.
我在尽全力绘制地图
And more and more, I'm convinced
玛丽 我越来越坚信
that nothing in our lifetime, Mary,
在我们有生之年
n-nothing in-in maybe all of recorded history
甚...甚至在整个人类记录的历史中
means more than this.
没什么比这更重要了
But I don't understand it. I don't...
可我就是没搞明白
I-I can't even describe it.
我...我根本说不上来
It...
这...
It's like describing a dog to someone who's never seen a dog.
这就好比给个没见过狗的人形容狗
And then asking them to draw it.
然后让那人把狗画出来
Now you want me to... describe it.
现在你想让我...形容它
And then you'll write it down, and then what?
然后你记下来 之后呢？
- Mary-- - You'll let me go?
- 玛丽... - 之后我就能走了吗？
We all want the same thing here.
其实咱们想的一样
We do.
真的
We just want to find out even a little bit more.
咱们都只想 哪怕能多弄懂一点点
What's gonna happen to me, Phil?
菲尔 我最后会怎么样？
That decision's not up to me.
这不是我能左右的
So...
那...
if we could just talk, just you and me,
咱们能不能就简单聊聊 就咱俩
you know, just like... just like two regular people.
就像...就像普通人那样
We could unpack some of this, we've both been in there,
咱们摊开聊聊 毕竟咱俩都进去过
and-and-and get on the same page.
这样咱...咱们才能把话说到一块儿去
There are doors opening everywhere.
现在 到处都在出现开启的门
We don't know why or what's connecting them.
我们搞不懂是啥把这些连在一起的
They sort of keep happening, and...
没完没了地出现
and we don't know how to stop them...
我们完全不知道怎么让它停下来...
（山脊公寓楼盘）
（《心灵之窗》）
（寻人启事 凯瑟琳·泰勒 罗博特·富兰克林）
（庭家科牙所诊 莱米饣布服）
（长克船的具家国帝）
导演
凯恩·帕森斯
编剧
威尔·苏迪克
改编自凯恩·帕森斯
系列视频
制片人
温子仁
迈克尔·克利尔
罗伯托·帕蒂诺
制片人
肖恩·利维
丹·科恩
丹·李文
制片人
奥兹·柏金斯
克里斯·费格森
制片人
彼得·切宁
詹诺·托平
科里·阿德尔森
摄影
杰里米·考克斯
剪辑
格雷格·吴
配乐
艾多·凡布利曼
凯恩·帕森斯
字幕译制
蒙太奇字幕组
字幕贡献者
翻译/校对/时间轴： 小p
校对：Ariel, Ke, Hypnotism, Balding
后期：NEST, NickCollect
Telegram/IRC：MontageSubs
蒙太奇字幕组社群
CC BY-NC-SA 4.0
字幕许可
主演
切瓦特·艾乔福 饰 家具店老板克拉克
雷娜特·赖因斯夫 饰 心理医生玛丽
主演
马克·杜普拉斯 饰 异步研究员菲尔
芬恩·班尼特 饰 小凯男友阿博
主演
卢琪塔·马克斯韦尔 饰 克拉克助理小凯
阿万·乔贾 饰 异步雇员纳伦·沃恩
罗伯特·博布罗茨基 饰 海盗版克拉克
凯恩·帕森斯
导演作品
（A24影业）
蒙太奇字幕组 (MontageSubs)
用爱发电 ♥ Powered by Love